Register of the Ardashīr Zāhidī papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Ambassador to the United States File, 1970-1979
  - Embassy files, 1970-1978
    - 1978 press correspondence, 1977-1978
      - Paz, Sarah Sayad, 1977-1978 (Box 120, Folder 8)
        Includes flier for Iranian Students Association; Assyrian Chronicle 1, no. 4 (1977), and Āshūr/Atour: The Assyrian Political, Social, and Cultural Newspaper (newspaper in English, Persian, and Syriac), no.154 (February 4, 1978).
      - R, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 9)
      - Rowan, Carl T., 1978 (Box 120, Folder 10-11)
      - S, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 12-13)
      - Schlosser, Herbert S., 1977-1978 (Box 120, Folder 14)
      - Scott, Frank, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 15)
      - Stackelberg, Garnett, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 16)
      - Stone, Marvin L., 1978 (Box 120, Folder 17)
      - Swinton, Stanley M., 1978 (Box 120, Folder 18)
      - T, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 19)
        Includes issue of Embassy News 2, no. 5 (May 1978).
      - Time, Inc., 1977-1978 (Box 121, Folder 1, Box 120, Folder 20)
        Includes correspondence with Robert B. Burns.
      - Udell, Paul, 1978 August 24 (Box 121, Folder 2)
      - Valeriani, Richard, 1978 January-February (Box 121, Folder 3)
      - W, 1977-1978 (Box 121, Folder 4)
      - Wallace, Mike, 1978 December (Box 121, Folder 5)
      - Washington Dossier, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 6)
      - Washington Post, 1977-1978 (Box 121, Folder 7)
      - Washington Star, 1978 January 4-5 (Box 121, Folder 8)
      - Weil, Gordon Lee, 1977-1978 (Box 121, Folder 9)
        Includes copy of interview with Hushang Ansary.
      - Whedon, Peggy, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 10)
    - 1978 state visit files
      - Farah Pahlavi in the United States, 1978 January (Box 121, Folder 11)
        Includes copies and drafts of letters from Farah Pahlavi to Jimmy and Rosalynn Carter.
      - Royal children's visit - San Francisco, 1978 July (Box 121, Folder 12-13)
        Consists of Zahedi's letters to hotel, security, and Allis-Chalmers staff.
      - Royal children's visit - Los Angeles, 1978 July (Box 121, Folder 14-15)
        Consists of Zahedi's letters to hotel and touristic staff, as well as other people the children met.
      - Royal children's visit, 1978 July (Box 121, Folder 16)
      - Letters received regarding royal children's visit, 1978 July-August (Box 121, Folder 17-19)
    - 1978 holiday files
      Includes gift lists, cards, telegrams, and responses.
      - July 4, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 20)
      - Birthday, 1978 October (Box 122, Folder 1-2)
      - Eid al-Adha, 1978 November (Box 122, Folder 3)
      - Christmas, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 4-11)
    - 1979 White House correspondence, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 122, Folder 12)
    - 1979 Correspondence with government officials, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 122, Folder 13)
    - 1979 US Senate correspondence, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - 1979 US House of Representatives correspondence, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - 1979 general correspondence, 1978-1979
      - A, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 3)
      - B, 1978 December - January 1979 (Box 123, Folder 4)
        Includes a letter from Barbara Bush.
      - C, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 5)
      - D, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 6)
      - F, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 7)
      - G, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 8)
      - H, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 9)
      - I, 1979 January 18 (Box 123, Folder 10)
      - J, 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 11)
      - K, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 12)
      - L, 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 13)
      - M, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 14-15)
      - N, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 16)
      - O, 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 17)
      - P, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 123, Folder 18)
      - R, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 124, Folder 1)
      - S, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 124, Folder 2)
      - T, 1978 December (Box 124, Folder 3)
      - V, 1979 January (Box 124, Folder 4)
      - W, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 124, Folder 5)
      - Y-Z, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - 1979 press correspondence, 1978 December - 1979 January (Box 124, Folder 7-10)
    - Iranian correspondence, 1973-1978
      "Rijāl-i Īrānī." Correspondents include diplomats, politicians, journalists, and personal contacts. Correspondence is chiefly in Persian, with some in English and French.
      Orginial order has been maintained, and correspondence is loosely organized in Persian alphabetical order.
      - Ārām, ʻAbbās, 1973-1978 (Box 125, Folder 1-3)
      - Imāmī, Sayyid Ḥasan, 1973-1978 (Box 125, Folder 4-6)
      - Ibtihāj, Abū al-Ḥasan,‏, 1973 (Box 125, Folder 7)
        Also spelled Abol Hassan Ebtehaj.
      - Isfandiyārī, Riz̤ā, 1973-1977 (Box 125, Folder 8)
        Also spelled Reza Esfandiari.
      - Amīrānī, ʻAlī Aṣghar, 1973-1978 (Box 125, Folder 9-10)
        Includes issues of Khvāndanīha 34, no. 99 (September 3, 1974), and photographs of Farid Amirani.
      - Ārāstah, Riz̤ā, 1971-1973 (Box 125, Folder 11)
        Also spelled A. Reza Arasteh.
      - Afshār, Amīr Aṣlān, Shīrīn, va Amīr Khusraw, 1973-1978 (Box 125, Folder 12-13)
        Includes report prepared by Amir Aslan Afshar on the Shah's statements regarding oil and its effect on the economy in the Federal Republic of Germany.
      - Azhārī, Ghulām Riz̤ā, 1973-1978 (Box 125, Folder 14)
        Also spelled Gholamreza Azhari.
      - Arjumand, Murtaḍā Amīr, 1973-1978 (Box 125, Folder 15)
      - Īlkhān, Ghulām Riz̤ā, 1973 (Box 125, Folder 16)
        Also spelled Gholam Reza Ilkhan.
      - Aḥmadī, Aḥmad ʻAlī va Ashraf, 1973-1977 (Box 125, Folder 17)
      - Intikhābī, A.H., 1973 July-August (Box 125, Folder 18)
      - Anṣārī, Hūshang, 1973-1976 (Box 125, Folder 19)
        Also spelled Hushang Ansary.
      - Ardalān, Humāyūn va Aḥmad, 1973-1976 (Box 125, Folder 20)
      - Afkhamī, Ṣafīyah, 1973 (Box 126, Folder 1)
      - Īlbagī, Parī, 1973 August (Box 126, Folder 2)
      - Iqbāl, Manūchihr, Khusraw, va Aḥmad, 1973-1978 (Box 126, Folder 3-4)
        Also spelled Manouchehr Eghbal.
      - Iskandar Mīrzā, Nāhīd, 1973-1976 (Box 126, Folder 5)
      - Isfandiyārī, Maḥmūd va Ḥusayn ʻAlī, 1973-1977 (Box 126, Folder 6)
        Also spelled Mahmoud Esfandiary.
      - Afkhamī, Manṣūr, 1973 December (Box 126, Folder 7)
      - Amīn, Riz̤ā, 1973 December (Box 126, Folder 8)
      - Umanāʼ, Mahdī, 1974-1977 (Box 126, Folder 9-10)
        Also spelled Mehdi Omana. Includes photographs of the Shah and Farah Pahlavi, presumably with Mehdi Omana.
      - Āshtiyānī, Rukn al-Dīn, 1974 and undated (Box 126, Folder 11)
      - Ardalān, ʻAlī Qulī va Amān Allāh, 1974-1977 (Box 126, Folder 12)
        Also spelled Ali Gholi Ardalan.
      - Īzadī, Ḥasan, 1974-1978 (Box 126, Folder 13)
      - Iskandarī, ʻAzīzallāh, 1974-1977 (Box 126, Folder 14)
      - Uvaysī, Ghulām ʻAlī, 1974-1978 (Box 126, Folder 15)
        Also spelled Gholam Ali Oveissi.
      - Ishrāqī, Ḥusayn, 1974-1978 (Box 126, Folder 16)
        Also spelled Hossein T. Eshraghi.
      - Ilāhī, Kāmbīz va Tashakkurī, 1974-1977 (Box 126, Folder 17)
      - Iṣfahānī, Qamar, 1974 December (Box 126, Folder 18)
        Also spelled Ghamar Ispahani.
      - Anṣārī, ʻAlī Naqī Saʻīd, 1975 April-May (Box 126, Folder 19)
      - Amīr Taymūr, Muḥammad Riz̤ā, 1975-1977 (Box 126, Folder 20)
      - Ittiḥādīyah, Sīmīn, 1976 (Box 126, Folder 21)
      - Atābakī, Batūl va Dāryūsh, 1976-1977 (Box 126, Folder 22)
      - Afshār, Amīr Khusraw, 1978 March (Box 126, Folder 23)
      - Bātmānqilīch, Hūshang, 1973-1978 (Box 127, Folder 1-4)
        Also spelled Houshang Batmanglidj or Batmanghelij. Includes correspondence with Shahnaz and Shirmin Batmanqlich, General Matbui, and notes and photocopies from the Congressional Record relating to the Emergency Security Act of 1973.
      - Bihdād, Ābidīn, 1978 (Box 127, Folder 5)
      - Bakhtiyārī, Malikshāh Ẓafar, 1973 (Box 127, Folder 6)
      - Bahādurī, Aḥmad, 1973-1976 (Box 127, Folder 7)
        Also spelled Bahadori.
      - Bihbūdī, Sulaymān, 1973-1977 (Box 127, Folder 8)
        Also spelled Suleiman Behboudi.
      - Bakhtiyār, Karīm, 1973 October-November (Box 127, Folder 9)
      - Bātmānqilīch, Nādir, 1974 (Box 127, Folder 10)
        Also spelled Nader Batmanghelidj. Includes copies of family travel documents and notes from a telephone conversation.
      - Bahrāmī, Aḥmad ʻAlī, 1974-1976 (Box 127, Folder 11)
      - Bīgdilī, Anvar Masʻūd, 1974-1975 (Box 127, Folder 12)
      - Bersabé Hovsepian, 1974-1978 (Box 127, Folder 13)
        Includes photograph of Bersabé with Galust M. Babakhanian and others.
      - Barāhanī, Riz̤ā, 1976 (Box 127, Folder 14)
        Also spelled Reza Baraheni. Includes photocopy and English translation of letter from Baraheni to Houshang Nahavandi and transcription of interview with Baraheni.
      - Partavī, Farīmā, 1973 April-May (Box 127, Folder 15)
      - Partavī, Nāhīd, 1973-1978 (Box 127, Folder 16-20)
        Also spelled Partovi. Includes Selected Poems from the Divan of Khaje Shams al-Din Hafiz of Shiraz; photographs, negatives, and slides depicting artwork from Iranian artists; correspondence between Gholam H. Kazemian and Roy Slade; and photographs of Mohammad Reza and Farah Pahlavi. Glass slides are stored separately.
      - Pīrniyā, Dāriyūsh, ʻAlī, Bāqir, Duktur, ʻIzzat, va Liyūsā, 1974-1978 (Box 127, Folder 21, Box 128, Folder 1-3)
      - Panāhī, Bahrām, 1974 September 5 (Box 128, Folder 4)
      - Tihrānī, Aḥmad, 1973-1976 (Box 128, Folder 5-6)
        Also spelled Tehrani.
      - Tavakkulī, Jaʻfar, 1973 September (Box 128, Folder 7)
      - Tāj Bakhsh, Ghulām Riz̤ā, 1974, 1978 (Box 128, Folder 8)
      - Tafaz̤z̤ulī, Jahāngīr, 1974-1975 (Box 128, Folder 9)
        Also spelled Jahangir Tafazoli.
      - Jam, Farīdūn, 1973-1977 (Box 128, Folder 10)
        Also spelled Fereydūn Djām
      - Jahānbānī, Manṣūr va Amīr, 1973-1978 (Box 128, Folder 11)
        Includes photograph of Fazlollah Zahedi and correspondence with Nasser Jehanbani.
      - Jahānbānī, Ḥusayn, Ḥamīd, va Majīd, 1974-1976 (Box 128, Folder 12)
      - Jamālzādah, Muḥammad ʻAlī, 1975 March (Box 128, Folder 13)
      - Ḥātim, Jamāl, 1973-1977 (Box 128, Folder 14-15)
        Also spelled Djamal Hatam.
      - Ḥātamī, Shāhrukh, 1973 (Box 128, Folder 16)
        Also spelled Shahrokh Hatami.
      - Ḥamzavī, ʻAbd al-Ḥusayn, 1973-1978 (Box 128, Folder 17-18)
        Includes copies of the Iran supplement to Japan Times.
      - Ḥāji Vahhābʹzādah va-khānavādah, 1973-1974 (Box 128, Folder 19)
      - Ḥikmat, ʻAlī Aṣghar, 1974 (Box 128, Folder 20)
        Also known as Hekmat E. Shirazi.
      - Ḥikmat, Saʻīd, 1974-1978 (Box 128, Folder 21)
        Also spelled Said Hekmat. Includes polaroid of Zahedi.
      - Khusrawʹdād, Manūchihr, 1973-1978 (Box 129, Folder 1-2)
        Also spelled Manouchehr Khosrodad.
      - Khādim, ʻAlī, 1973-1977 (Box 129, Folder 3)
        Also spelled Ali Khadem.
      - Khaṭībī, Aḥmad, 1978 January-February (Box 129, Folder 4)
      - Khātamī, Muḥammad Amīr, 1973-1975 (Box 129, Folder 5)
      - Khazāʻī, Tūrān, 1974 February-April (Box 129, Folder 6)
      - Khalʻatʹbarī, Arsalān, 1974-1975 (Box 129, Folder 7)
        Includes issue of Khvāndanīha 34, no. 99 (February 19, 1974).
      - Khvānsārī, Parvīz, 1974 March-April (Box 129, Folder 8)
        Also spelled Parviz Khonsari.
      - Khalʻatʹbarī, Sayf al-Dīn va S̲urayyā, 1974-1978 (Box 129, Folder 9)
      - Dāvarī, Hūshang, 1973-1977 (Box 129, Folder 10)
      - Dāvarī, Ḥusayn, 1973 (Box 129, Folder 11)
        Includes İran: Ak Devrimin Getirdikleri, a book by Kenan Esengin published by İstanbul Matbaacilik, and a translation of a small section in Persian.
      - Dānishvar, Ḥusayn, 1973-1976 (Box 129, Folder 12)
      - Darvīsh, Pūrān, 1973-1976 (Box 129, Folder 13)
      - Dībā, Aḥmad, 1974 April (Box 129, Folder 14)
      - Dashtī, ʻAlī, 1974 (Box 129, Folder 15)
      - Davallū, Amīr Hūshang va Munīr Aʻẓam, 1974-1977 (Box 129, Folder 16)
      - Raymūnd, Parī, 1973 July (Box 129, Folder 17)
      - Raz̤avī, Hūshang, 1973-1978 (Box 129, Folder 18-20)
      - Rāʼīn, Ismaʻīl, 1976 April (Box 129, Folder 21)
        Includes copies of telegraphs and letters from 1942 between English politicians regarding Fazlollah and the tribes in Chaharmahal and Bakhtiari Province.
      - Zāhidī, Abū al-Qāsim, 1973-1976 (Box 129, Folder 22)
        Includes write-up on the development of a sheep and goat institute in Iran.
      - Zāhidī, Riz̤ā va Zahdī, 1974-1977 (Box 129, Folder 23)
      - Zandfard, Farīdūn, 1973-1977 (Box 130, Folder 1-2)
      - Zāhidī, Gisèle va ʻIshrat, 1973, 1975 (Box 130, Folder 3)
      - Zāhidī, Ḥasan, 1973, 1975 (Box 130, Folder 4)
      - Zāhidī, Fīrūz, Farrukh, va Naṣr Allāh, 1973-1978 (Box 130, Folder 5)
      - Zāhidī, Naṣr va Parvīz, 1974-1976 (Box 130, Folder 6)
      - Zand, Humā va Fāṭimah, 1974 February-March (Box 130, Folder 7)
      - Zāhidī, Fāṭimah, Abū al-Fatḥ va Hūshang, 1973-1977 (Box 130, Folder 8)
      - Saljūqī, Faz̤l Allāh, 1973-1978 (Box 130, Folder 9)
      - Sipahbudī, Farhād, 1973-1977 (Box 130, Folder 10)
        Also spelled Farhad Sepahbody.
      - Sutūdah, Farīdūn va Bāqir, 1973-1978 (Box 130, Folder 11-12)
        Also spelled Sotoudeh. Includes letter from Faridun to Abbas Ali Khalatbari.
      - Sardār Fākhir, Riz̤ā, 1975-1977 (Box 130, Folder 13)
        Also known as Riz̤ā Ḥikmat.
      - Sörensen, Philip, 1973-1975 (Box 130, Folder 14-15)
        Also known as Sven Philip-Sörensen. Includes a translation of an article from Kvällsposten and photographs of Zahedi.
      - Samāʼī, Bahrām, 1977-1978 (Box 130, Folder 16)
      - Saʻīd Anṣārī, ʻAlīnaqī, 1973 (Box 130, Folder 17)
      - Samīʻī, Hurmuz, Abd al-Ḥusayn va Zahrā, 1973-1978 (Box 130, Folder 18-19)
      - Sanandajī, Sulṭān Ḥusayn, 1974 March-April (Box 130, Folder 20)
      - Sazāvār, Nayr al-Dīn, 1974-1978 (Box 130, Folder 21)
      - Sarābandī, Ṭalʻat, 1974-1978 (Box 130, Folder 22)
      - Shafā, Shuʻāʻ al-Dīn, 1973 August 19-22 (Box 131, Folder 1)
      - Shīlātī, Amīr, 1973-1975 (Box 131, Folder 2)
      - Shahīdzādah, Ḥusayn, 1973-1978 (Box 131, Folder 3-4)
      - Schott, Robert, 1973-1976 (Box 131, Folder 5-7)
        Includes reports on Iran's economy authored by Dr. Mahoutdji and issued by Bānk-i Īrāniyān (Iranians' Bank).
      - Shādāb, 1973-1976 (Box 131, Folder 8)
        One of the correspondents is Khusraw.
      - Shīrīn, Ismāʻīl, 1973-1978 (Box 131, Folder 9)
        Also spelled Ismail Chirine.
      - Shāhvash, 1973-1975 (Box 131, Folder 10)
      - Sharīf Imāmī, Jaʻfar, 1978 August-October (Box 131, Folder 11)
        Also spelled Jafar Sharif-Emami. Includes message from Sharif-Emami to President Carter.
      - Shīrzād, Nāṣir, 1978 July-August (Box 131, Folder 12)
        Includes letter from Khalatbari to Nasir Shirzad.
      - Ṣadīq Isfandiyārī, Muḥsin, 1973-1976 (Box 131, Folder 13)
        Also spelled Mohsen Sadigh Esfandiary. Includes letter from Vibhavadi Rangsit and applications for employment with the Iranian embassy in the United States.
      - Ṣaffārī, Maḥmūd, 1973 June-July (Box 131, Folder 14)
      - Ṣāḥib Qalam, N., 1973 September (Box 131, Folder 15)
      - Ṣayrafī, Abū al-Ḥasan, 1973 (Box 131, Folder 16)
      - Ṣafīʹniyā, Parvīz, Hūshang va Farīburz, 1973-1977 (Box 131, Folder 17-18)
        Also spelled Parviz Safinia.
      - Ṣādiq, Ḥusayn, 1974 (Box 131, Folder 19)
      - Ṣadrīyah, Ṣādiq, 1976 November-December (Box 131, Folder 20)
      - Ṣādiqī, Ḥusayn, 1977 (Box 131, Folder 21)
        Also spelled Sadeghi. Includes Savak report about him and his son's alleged communist activities.
      - Ṭūfāniyān, Ḥasan, 1974-1975 (Box 131, Folder 22)
      - Ṭāhirī, Amīr, 1973-1976 (Box 131, Folder 23)
        Also spelled Amir Taheri. Includes prints of newspaper photos of Zahedi with the Shah.
      - Ẓilī, Manūchihr, 1973-1978 (Box 131, Folder 24)
      - ʻAẓīmā, Āvīdah va Manūchihr, 1973-1977 (Box 131, Folder 25)
      - ʻAdl, Murtaz̤á, 1973-1978 (Box 132, Folder 1)
      - ʻAz̤ud, Abū Naṣr, 1973-1978 (Box 132, Folder 2)
        Also spelled Abounasr Azod. Includes copy of telegram from Prince Azod to Jean-Claude Duvalier.
      - ʻAṣṣār, Naṣīr, 1973-1978 (Box 132, Folder 3)
      - ʻAlīzādah, Mahdī, circa 1970s (Box 132, Folder 4)
      - ʻAlāʼ, Farīdūn, 1976-1977 (Box 132, Folder 5)
      - ʻAdl, Parvīz, 1973-1977 (Box 132, Folder 6-7)
      - ʻĀmilī, ʻIzzat Allāh, 1974 January-March (Box 132, Folder 8)
      - ʻAlīkhānī, 1973 March-April (Box 132, Folder 9)
      - ʻAbduh, Jalāl, 1974-1976 (Box 132, Folder 10)
      - ʻAbqarī, Ḥusayn, 1974 (Box 132, Folder 11)
      - Ghaffārī, Aḥmad, 1973-1978 (Box 132, Folder 12-14)
        Includes copy of clipping with Ghaffari's letter to the International Herald Tribune.
      - Ghaffārī, ʻAbbās, 1973-1976 (Box 132, Folder 15)
      - Fīrūz, Shāhrukh, Ṣafīyah va Muḥammad Ḥusayn Mīrzā, 1973-1976 (Box 132, Folder 16)
      - Fīrūz, Muẓaffar, circa 1970s (Box 132, Folder 17)
        Consists of written Persian translation of newspaper interview with Muzaffar in the Courrier.
      - Farzānagān, ʻAbbās va Amīr, 1973-1977 (Box 132, Folder 18)
        Also spelled Farzenegan.
      - Fuyūz̤ī, Riz̤ā, 1973-1976 (Box 132, Folder 19)
        Also spelled Foyouzi.
      - Farmānʹfarmāyān, Parvīn va Tūraj, 1973 August, 1976 June (Box 132, Folder 20)
      - Fīlī, Farīdah, 1973 May (Box 132, Folder 21)
      - Fīrūzmand, Nāṣir, 1973 September-October (Box 132, Folder 22)
      - Fardānish, Parvīn, 1973 June (Box 132, Folder 23)
      - Farzānagān, ʻAzīz, 1973 February 20 (Box 132, Folder 24)
      - Fartāsh, Manūchihr, 1974-1975 (Box 132, Folder 25)
      - Farzānah, Sīrūs, 1974 March-April (Box 132, Folder 26)
        Includes photograph of Zahedi from his youth.
      - Fāṭimī, ʻAlī Muḥammad, 1974 (Box 132, Folder 27)
      - Fahīmī, Asadallāh, Maryam va Nasrīn Amīr Aṣlānī, 1975-1977 (Box 132, Folder 28)
      - Qarīb, Zhālah, 1973 February (Box 133, Folder 1)
      - Qiyāyī, Manūchihr, circa 1970s (Box 133, Folder 2)
      - Qadīrī, Zhīlā, 1973 (Box 133, Folder 3)
      - Qubādiyān, Gītī, 1973 November 5-12 (Box 133, Folder 4)
      - Qadar, Manṣūr, 1973-1977 (Box 133, Folder 5)
      - Qashqāʼī, Muḥammad Nāṣir va Nāhīd, 1974-1978 (Box 133, Folder 6)
      - Qurayshī, Ḥasan, 1976-1978 (Box 133, Folder 7)
        Also spelled Goreschi.
      - Qarāguzlū, ʻAz̲rā, 1976 June (Box 133, Folder 8)
      - Kāẓimī, Firishtah va ʻIz al-Dīn, 1973-1976 (Box 133, Folder 9)
        Also spelled Kazemi.
      - Kafāʼī, ʻAbd al-Ḥusayn, 1973 April (Box 133, Folder 10)
        Also spelled Abdolhossein Kafai.
      - Kiyā, Nūr al-Dīn, 1973-1975 (Box 133, Folder 11)
      - Kalhur, Manṣūrah, 1973-1974 (Box 133, Folder 12)
      - ʻAlavī Kiyā, Ḥasan, 1973-1974 (Box 133, Folder 13)
        Also known as Hassan Alavikia.
      - Kūpāl, Dāryūsh, 1976 May-June (Box 133, Folder 14)
      - Ganjī, Manūchihr, 1973-1974 (Box 133, Folder 15)
        Also spelled Manouchehr Ganji.
      - Ganjī, Shahlā, 1974-1975 (Box 133, Folder 16)
        Includes typewritten poem, "Shurūʻ-i zindagī."
      - Malāyirī, ʻAbbās, 1973-1974 (Box 133, Folder 17)
      - Mirʼāt, Parvīz, 1973 February (Box 133, Folder 18)
        Also spelled Parviz Merat.
      - Mukhāṭib Rāfiʻī, Ḥabīb Allāh, 1973-1975 (Box 133, Folder 19)
      - Mustawfī, Bāqir, 1973-1978 (Box 133, Folder 20)
      - Mālik, Shāhrukh, 1973 March-May (Box 133, Folder 21)
      - Muhannā, Siyāvash va Manūchihr, 1973-1978 (Box 133, Folder 22-23)
        Also spelled Siavashe Mohanna.
      - Marzbān, Manūchihr, 1973-1974 (Box 133, Folder 24)
      - Mirʼāt Isfandiyārī, Muḥsin, 1973 July-August (Box 133, Folder 25)
      - Mīrfandaraskī, Aḥmad, circa 1973-1978 (Box 133, Folder 26)
        Usually spelled Mirfendereski.
      - Māzandī, Yūsuf, 1973-1977 (Box 133, Folder 27)
      - Muʻallim-i Vālāḥaz̤rat Mahnāz, 1973 January 28 (Box 133, Folder 28)
      - Muẓaffar, Mālik, 1973 September (Box 133, Folder 29)
        Also spelled Mozaffar Malek.
      - Mīnāʼī, Aḥmad, 1973-1978 (Box 133, Folder 30)
      - Mubaṣṣir, Muḥsin, 1973-1974 (Box 133, Folder 31)
      - Mūlānū,Qudsī, 1973-1978 (Box 133, Folder 32)
        Includes correspondence with Henrique Molano Campuzano. Also spelled Qodsi Molano.
      - Masʻūdī, ʻAbbās va bānū, 1973-1978 (Box 133, Folder 33)
        Includes correspondence with Farhād Masʻūdī, also spelled Massoudi.
      - Maḥvī, Abū al-Fatḥ, 1974, 1978 (Box 133, Folder 34)
      - Majīdī, ʻAbd al-Majīd, 1973-1974 (Box 134, Folder 1)
        Includes correspondence with Hamid Tabrizi.
      - Mushīrī, Riz̤ā, 1974 (Box 134, Folder 2)
      - Muʻtamidī, ʻAlī, 1974 July-August (Box 134, Folder 3)
      - Mushīrfāṭimī, Mulūk va Ṣafīyah Ṣadīq, 1976-1977 (Box 134, Folder 4)
      - Majd, Nāṣir, 1975-1978 (Box 134, Folder 5)
      - Masʻūd, khānavādah, 1976-1978 (Box 134, Folder 6)
        Includes correspondence with Asghar Massoud.
      - Muqaddam, Nāṣir, 1977-1978 (Box 134, Folder 7)
        Also spelled Nasser Moghadam.
      - Nashā't, Mahyār, 1973-1974 (Box 134, Folder 8)
      - Nafīsī, Ḥabīb va Aḥmad, 1973-1975 (Box 134, Folder 9)
      - Narāqī, Iḥsān, circa 1970s (Box 134, Folder 10)
      - Naṣīrī, Niʻmat Allāh, 1973-1978 (Box 134, Folder 11)
        Also spelled Nematollah Nassiri.
      - Nīkʹpūr, Manūchihr, 1973 June (Box 134, Folder 12)
      - Navāʼī, Afrāsiyāb, 1973 (Box 134, Folder 13)
      - Nayyirī, ʻAbbās, 1973 November, 1976 April (Box 134, Folder 14)
        Also spelled Nayeri.
      - Nūrī Isfandiyārī, ʻAlī, 1973 November, 1976 (Box 134, Folder 15)
      - Niẓām Māfī, Muḥammad ʻAlī, 1974 January-March (Box 134, Folder 16)
      - Nāẓirī, Īrān, 1974 January-March (Box 134, Folder 17)
      - Narāqī, Ḥashmat, 1974 February (Box 134, Folder 18)
      - Nahāvandī, Hūshang, 1974-1978 (Box 134, Folder 19)
        Includes report, probably written by Nahavandi, about the Shah's revolution.
      - Nuṣratiyān, Qudsī, 1974-1975 (Box 134, Folder 20)
      - Naṣrī, Qulī, 1978 April-May (Box 134, Folder 21)
      - Vakīl, Mahdī, 1973-1978 (Box 134, Folder 22-24)
        Also spelled Mehdi Vekil. Includes Italian magazine articles about Savak and Iranian political refugees in Rome, with a French translation of the article about political refugees, and illustrations of antique items.
      - Valiyān, ʻAbd al-ʻAẓīm, 1973-1974 (Box 134, Folder 25)
      - Washington Post, 1973 April-May (Box 134, Folder 26)
        Consists of letters in response to an article about Zahedi in the Washington Post.
      - Vārastah, Manūchihr, 1976-1977 (Box 134, Folder 27)
        Also spelled Manoochehr Varasteh.
      - Hudá, Faz̤l ʻAlī, 1973-1978 (Box 134, Folder 28)
      - Hīrād, Ḥusayn ʻAlī, 1973 (Box 135, Folder 1)
      - Hidāyat, Khusraw va Akhtar, 1973-1976 (Box 135, Folder 2)
        Also spelled Khosrow Hedayat.
      - Hidāyatī, Muḥammad ʻAlī va Hādī, 1977 (Box 135, Folder 3)
        Includes photograph with Zahedi.